careerwebsite.com 2019-09-13

# YourMembership Privacy Policy | Legal Terms & Conditions

### Introduction

YourMembership is a member of the Community Brands family. This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) is specific to YourMembership. This is due to the specific services and software uniquely provided by YourMembership. Please also review the Community Brands Privacy Policy to ensure you are fully informed of our privacy practices. The Community Brands Privacy Policy can be found here: <https://www.communitybrands.com/legal/>.

At YourMembership.com, Inc. (“YM”, “we”, “us”, “our”, or the “Company”), we are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains the way we collect, share and use personal information about you, and how you can exercise your privacy rights. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we collect about users of our websites and is designed to help you understand how we collect, use and safeguard the information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Services.

This Privacy Policy only applies to websites owned and operated by YourMembership, including, but not limited to, www.yourmembership.com (the “Websites”) and services provided by or enabled via the Websites including: YourMembership AMS, Career Center and Crowd Wisdom LMS (together the “Services”).  
By using our Websites or Services, or otherwise providing us with your information, you consent to us collecting, holding, using and disclosing your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we are not able to collect, handle, use and disclose personal information about you as set out in this Privacy Policy, we may not be able to provide you with our Services or with access to our Websites.

### Links to other websites

We may provide links to other websites operated by third parties. YourMembership is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of any third party website that YourMembership website may link to. Also, YourMembership is not responsible for the privacy practices of our clients or users of our clients’ websites. Our clients are the organizations for which we provide outsourced services in relation to your membership application, your job or other role application or education or training you receive. You should review any additional privacy policy and terms of use agreements before using a client’s website as their terms of use and privacy policy may differ from ours.

### YourMembership Software Platforms

In addition to the Websites, YourMembership operates web-based software platforms, YourMembership Association Management Software (“YourMembership AMS”), Crowd Wisdom Learning Management Software (“Crowd Wisdom LMS”) and Career Center solutions, used by our clients to provide services to their employees and customers (“YourMembership Platforms”). Our use of information collected through this these platforms is strictly limited to the purpose of meeting our contractual obligations to our clients and providing the services requested by our clients, which are defined within our service agreements.  
If you are the customer of one of our clients (also known as an “end-user”), you should also refer to that client’s privacy policy for information on how the client uses your personal information. Any inquires related to your data, how it is processed, and data access, deletion and modification requests should be directed to that client.

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. The most current version is located at https://www.yourmembership.com/legal/ and can also be requested using the contact details provided under the section headed “How to Contact Us” below.  
For further information on your rights with respect to changes to the Privacy Policy, please see the section entitled “Further details on Changes to the Privacy Policy”.

### Policy Regarding Children

YourMembership Websites and Services are not designed for use by children under the age of 16. As such, this Website is not directed at children under the age of 16 nor do we knowingly collect or maintain information from children under the age of 16 on this Website.

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

We collect your personal information when you use the Services and during the application process on YourMembership Platforms.

### Information that we obtain from other sources

We may receive personal information about you from our direct clients who ask us to process your personal information on their behalf. This information is collected only where we have checked that the organization either has your consent or are otherwise is legally permitted or required to disclose your personal information to us.

Unless otherwise stated on an application for the YourMembership Platform, the types of end-user data we collect from our clients includes name, address, mobile or cell phone details, email address and payment information.

### How do we use your personal information?

We use the personal information collected to conduct our business and communicate with you, to provide and market our services, to help us manage, develop and enhance our Websites and Services, and to comply with legal obligations.

If you are an end-user and your personal information is collected using YourMembership AMS, your personal information will be used to manage your account with our client. If you are a direct client of Yourmembership and your personal information is collected using Yourmemberhsip AMS, your personal information will be used to manage the account portal for your organization.

If you are an end-user and your personal information is collected using the Crowd Wisdom LMS, your personal information will be used to enable you to use the Crowd Wisdom LMS, and certify your completion of assessments and courses on the Crowd Wisdom LMS. If you are a direct client of Yourmembership and your personal information is collected using the Crowd Widsom LMS, your personal information will be used to administer the Crowd Wisdom LMS within your organization.

If you are an end-user and your personal information is collected using the Career Center solution, your personal information will be used to manage your Job Seeker account with our client. If you are a direct client of Yourmembership and your personal information is collected using the Career Center solution, your personal information will be used to manage your Employer account.

However, we may also use your personal information for other purposes that are not incompatible with the purposes we have disclosed to you (for instance statistical or historical research purposes or where required by law) if and where this is permitted by applicable data protection laws.  
For further information on the type of information we collect and how we use that information, please see the section entitled “Further Details on How We Use the Data We Collect”.

### Who do we share your information with?

We may disclose your personal information to the following categories of recipients:

  * clients to whom we are processing your personal information on their behalf;
  * to our affiliates and related companies;
  * to third party service providers and partners who assist us in providing our Website, YourMembership Platforms and Services (including hosting and data storage providers), or who otherwise process personal information for the purposes that are described in this Privacy Policy or notified to you when we collect your personal information;
  * to any law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary; and
  * to any other person with your consent to the disclosure.

For further information on who we share your information with, please see the section entitled “Further Details on How We Share Data”.

### Integrity of personal information

We will take such steps (if any) as are reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate, up-to-date, and complete, and that the personal information we use and disclose is accurate, up-to-date, complete and relevant (having regard to the purpose of the use or disclosure). To assist us, please ensure that the information you provide to us is accurate, up-to-date, and complete.

We will also take such steps (if any) as are reasonable in the circumstances to protect the personal information we collect and hold from misuse, interference and loss, and from unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.

If we hold personal information about you that is no longer needed for any purpose for which it may be used or disclosed, we will take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to destroy or permanently de-identify that personal information.

### Data Retention

We may retain your information for a period of time consistent with the original purpose of collection. For instance, we may retain your information during the time in which you have an account to use our Websites or Services and for a reasonable period afterward. We also may retain your information during the period of time needed for us to pursue our legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.  
When we no longer require your personal information, we will take reasonable steps to either destroy or de-identify it.

### International Data Transfers

Yourmembership is a U.S. based company. Data of our clients, as well as end-user data that is stored on YourMembership servers, is maintained in the USA.  
However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### European residents

For European Economic Area residents your personal information is transferred to the US in accordance with our privacy shield certification, as set out in the section entitled “EU-US Privacy Shield Framework”.

### Australian residents

For Australian residents, we comply with the obligations of the Privacy Act 1988 and the Australian Privacy Principles.

### Authority to Provide Personal Information

Do not provide personal information about others unless you are authorized or required to do so by applicable law or contract. Before supplying personal information about others, you and the person about whom you supply the information must review and consent to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy of the Website. By submitting any personal information about others, you represent and warrant that you are authorized to do so, that you have made the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy available to the person about whom you supply the information, and that you have obtained that person’s written consent to our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. If applicable law allows you to supply the information without doing the foregoing, you represent and warrant that you have abided by that law and that it allows us to receive and disclose the information under this Privacy Policy without any further action on our part. You agree to indemnify, defend and hold harmless YourMembership, our parents, subsidiaries, officers, directors, employees and agents, sponsors and supporting artists, licensors and suppliers for any failure by you to comply with this paragraph.

### Cookies and similar tracking technology

**Cookies**  
YourMembership may place “cookies” on the browser of your computer or other device. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive or your device’s memory. Cookies may enhance the convenience and use of the Website. For  
example, the information provided through cookies may be used to recognize you as a previous user of the Website (so you do not have to enter your personal information every time), offer personalized information for your use, and otherwise facilitate your experience using the Website. You may choose to decline cookies if your browser permits, but doing so may affect your ability to access or use certain features of the Website.

YourMembership may also utilize web beacons on our Websites. A “web beacon,” also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, links web pages to web servers and their cookies and may be used to transmit information collected through cookies back to a web server. The information collected through these automated means may include information that we gather and store about your visit to, and use of, the Websites, such as your IP address, type of browser and operating system used, date and time you access the websites, pages you visit, and, if you linked to the Websites from another website, the address of that website. This data does not include Personal Information and is not treated as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy, but it may include the IP address of your device. We may link an IP address to information that is personally identifiable.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can disable this function so that your browser will not accept cookies. Please be aware that disabling this function may impact your use and enjoyment of this Website.

**Third-Party Analytics**  
We may also allow certain third-party analytics service providers to include cookies and web beacons within the pages of the Websites on our behalf and to retain and use the information received from such cookies and web beacons themselves. Third-party service providers that collect this data on our behalf or on behalf of client may offer information about their data collection practices.

Do Not Track Currently, various browsers — including Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome, Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, and Apple Safari — offer a “do not track” or “DNT” option that relies on a technology known as a DNT header, which sends a signal to Web sites’ visited by the user about the user’s browser DNT preference setting. We do not currently commit to responding to browsers’ DNT signals with respect to the Company’s Web sites, in part, because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry groups, technology companies or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting user intent.

We take privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of a standard.

### EU-US Privacy Shield Framework

YourMembership complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. YourMembership has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.

YourMembership chooses our third-party agents with care and works to ensure they uphold privacy and security standards set forth by the Privacy Shield Framework. Regarding the Accountability for Onward Transfer, YourMembership remains liable if our agent processes the personal information, we have provided them in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we can provide prove that YourMembership is not responsible for any occurrence resulting in a compromise of personal data.

YourMembership is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission.  
YourMembership’s headquarters are in the United States and as such, data may be transferred to the United States. Personal data will be transferred to the United States only: to fulfill contractual obligations to you; with your consent; or to fulfill a compelling legitimate interest of YourMembership in a manner that does not impeach on your rights and freedoms. As we are compliant with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, we therefore comply with data protection requirements when transferring personal data from the EU. In addition, we make every effort to ensure the security and protection of the data we transfer.

**Marketing communications opt-out**  
You also have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority, the Federal Trade Commission, or the US Department of Commerce. Contact details for data protection authorities in the EEA and Australia are provided under the section entitled “EEA and Australian Data Protection Authorities” below.

### California Residents’ Privacy Rights

Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information with respect to the types of personal information the business  
shares with third parties for direct marketing purposes by such third party and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. To request a copy of such information, please contact us as described in the “How to Contact Us” section below, and we will respond within 30 days as required by law.

### Further Details on Collection and Use of Data

**Personal Information and Business Information**  
“Personal Information” as used in this Privacy Policy is information that we directly associate with a specific person or entity, such as name, address, payment information (including payment card number, expiration date, cardholder name and CVV code), mobile telephone number, and email address and also includes information or an opinion, whether true or not, about an identified individual or an individual who is reasonably identifiable. Personal Information includes Business Information which is defined below.

The Personal Information you provide will vary based upon the context, and we will not collect your Personal Information unless you make it available. You are not required to provide Personal Information at any time while visiting the Websites; however, you may be required to provide Personal Information to use certain Services. You may provide us with Personal Information by participating in online or emailed surveys, subscribing to newsletters and other recurring offerings through the Websites, and in connection with other products, services, features, or requests made available through the Websites.

YourMembership collects the Business and Personal Information necessary to enable us to respond to your requests for our products and services and to send you information regarding our products and services from time to time. Since most of the users of our products and Websites are doing so in their capacity as potential employees, employees, employers or companies, most Business and Personal Information we collect will be in that capacity. For these purposes, we have defined “Business Information” as any information that identifies or may identify a job seeker (potential employee), company or an individual contact at a company or that allows others to contact a company or an individual contact at a company. When you visit our Websites, you may be asked to submit information such as e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, your product version and/or areas of interest. We may also ask you where you heard about our company or products, or for other information that will help us understand more about your needs or help us process your requests for information. In addition, we collect credit card and related payment information when you order products, services or support plans online. Our information collection and use practices are described in more detail below.

### Support

We offer certain limited online support services. If you access our online support, you may be asked for information such as customer ID, product name, product version and other information to help us determine what the technical issues are and how best to help you resolve them. In addition, certain products allow you to submit support-related questions directly from the product. If you access online support services from a product, information about your network, operating system, printer, data and program path, product type, version, customer ID, the product’s technical support information sheet, product serial number and other similar information will be automatically pre-populated for submission to our customer support representatives to assist them in answering your questions.

### Product-Related Information Collection

YourMembership collects certain additional information in connection with your use of our Services, web-based products and/or desktop products with online features. For instance:

  * Product Updates: Some products provide you with the ability to download and register product and/or tax updates as they become available. During the download and registration process, we collect “Business Information”, including customer ID number and product version, type and serial number. This is collected so that we can authorize your access, provide you with the appropriate update, and to update our records as to the product and products updates you have downloaded or installed, so that we may provide the appropriate support.
  * Account Set-Up and Access: Upon subscribing to our services, YourMembership collects Business Information, which may include information such as product serial number, customer ID and your customer profile information. This allows us to identify you to authorize your access and use of the services, and to provide you with your relevant account information. Certain products allow you to access your account to obtain information such as your support plan status, service subscriptions, registrations and order history.
  * Online Product /Account Application: Certain products and services are subject to an application and enrollment process, which may be completed on paper or online. Information requested may include federal ID numbers, bank account, payroll, credit card and contact information. This information is used to process your enrollment request and, if approved, to set up and administer your account.
  * Web-based Services: Some of our web-based Services collect certain additional information, including IP address, browser, connection speed, domain, referring URL and other environment-related information. This enables us to provide a secure environment for the use of the services, to pre-populate forms and calculate aggregate statistical information about the customers using these services. We use this information to better protect you and to provide a better user experience.

### Third-Party Products

YourMembership may use your Business Information to inform you of special discounts or offers from other companies we have carefully selected and whose products and services may be of interest to you.

### Public Forums

Information (including personal and business information) that you submit, post or otherwise reveal in a public forum (such as comments to a blog or product discussion forum) is not subject to this Privacy Policy, will be seen by third parties not related to YourMembership and may be used by them or YourMembership to contact you for any purpose.

### Registrations

To access information (blogs, demos of our products, marketing materials etc.) on the Websites, a user may be required to register with YourMembership. During registration a user is required to give certain information (such as name, email address, job title). This information is used to contact you about the products/services on our website in which you have expressed interest.

### Orders

We request information from you on our order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we’ll use this information to contact you.

### Surveys and Contests

From time-to-time, our Websites may request information via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you may choose whether or not to participate and therefore disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify winners and award prizes, if applicable. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of the Website or for delivery of.

### Further Details on How We Use the Data We Collect

**Email Communication**  
Each email we send will contain instructions on how to unsubscribe should you decide not to receive future promotional e-mails. Please allow up to 10 business days to be removed from our promotional e-mail list.

We send notification emails about the Website and Services from time to time as necessary. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.  
Our Career Center solutions send notifications to job-seekers about relevant job information. If you are a job-seeker, you may opt out of these communications at any time.

For our Career Center solutions, YourMembership collects personal and non-personal information to perform the service of matching job seekers up with potential employers. To create a job seeker profile for you based on information you have provided to us; To provide information about you to employers and recruiters at your request; To create an employer profile based on the information you have provided us; To provide information about you and your recruitment advertisements to job seekers at your request; If an employer uses YourMembership’s technology to post an advertisement to a third party job board, that employer’s contact information may be shared with the operator of that third party; To contact you regarding changes to your profile, service updates, products and services you may be interested in, surveys, sweepstakes, and various other.

YourMembership acts as an agent of the employer by collecting user personal and non-personal information during the job application process.

**Third-Party E-Mail Promotions**  
If you access and/or use any of our Partner’s services from a link on this Website, a YourMembership/Partner co-branded website or by any other means, any information you reveal in connection with such service is submitted to our Partner and is not subject to this Privacy Policy. You should consult the privacy policy of any Partner or third-party website with respect to its treatment of any information that you may reveal through such service.

**Services and Product Data**  
Business Information collected by YourMembership as set forth in the Personal Information and Business Information section above does not include your company’s data entered in the course of operating our products (“Product Data“) or data provided by you while using our services  
(“Services Data“). YourMembership will not access your Product Data or Services Data except in the following limited circumstances:

  * to provide you with technical support, solely at your request and with your permission;
  * on a limited-access basis to install updates, produce regular backups or restore data from backups at your request;
  * where the inherent purpose of the product or service requires YourMembership to provide the Product Data or Services Data to a third party on your behalf (for example where YourMembership makes tax filings on your behalf or initiates bank transfers on your behalf); and
  * unless you opt-out, to utilize Aggregate Information derived from Product Data and Services Data to help us improve our products and services and in developing additional offerings. Aggregate Information is non-identifying information about you that is provided to third parties for analysis. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of this Website and the activities they conduct while on this Website to better understand user experience. Third-parties who receive aggregate information cannot identify or contact you based on the information they receive.

YourMembership will not provide your Product Data or Services Data to any third-party or permit any third-party to access your Product Data or Services Data, except with your permission or to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order. In addition, if at any time you decide to discontinue your use of the applicable service, your Services Data will be destroyed and removed from all servers according to terms set forth in your Service Agreement, subject to applicable back-up and disaster recovery practices and procedures.

### Further Details on How We Share Data

Unless you give us your permission, we don’t share data we collect from you with third parties, except as described below:  
Third-party service providers or consultants. We may share data collected from you on the YourMembership Website with third-party service providers or consultants who need access to the data to perform their work on YourMembership’s behalf, such as a website analytics company or our third-party advertising partners. These third-party service providers are limited to only accessing or using this data to provide services to us and must provide reasonable assurances that they will appropriately safeguard the data.

**Compliance with Laws**. We may disclose your data to a third party if (i) we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or government request (including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements), (ii) to enforce our agreements and policies, (iii) to protect the security or integrity of the YourMembership Website or our services and products, (iv) to protect ourselves, our other customers, or the public from harm or illegal activities, or (v) to respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith requires us to disclose data to assist in preventing a death or serious bodily injury. If YourMembership is required by law to disclose any of your data that directly identifies you, then we will use reasonable efforts to provide you with notice of that disclosure requirement, unless we are prohibited from doing so by statute, subpoena or court or administrative order. Further, we object to requests that we do not believe were issued properly.

**Affiliates**. We may share data collected from you from the YourMembership Website with our affiliates. We all will only use the data as described in this notice.  
Business transfers. If we go through a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, data we gather from you through our website may be part of the assets transferred or shared in connection with due diligence for any such transaction. Any acquirer or successor of YourMembership may continue to use the data we collect from you through our Website as described in this notice.

**Aggregated or de-identified data**. We might also share data collected from you from the YourMembership Website with a third party if that data has been de-identified or aggregated in a way that does not directly identify you.

**Employers (Career Center)**. An Employer is a recruiter, company representative, agency or other individual who has contracted with YourMembership and is interested in contacting potential candidates, or job-seekers, for job openings. Relevant job-seeker resumes are provided to Employers, who may use that resume information to contact the job-seeker. This information is only made available to employers with the consent of the job-seeker.  
We do not share our client data (including, but not limited to, the personal data of their “end-users”) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, unless consent has been given to do so.

However, if YourMembership sells assets (or the assets of a division or subsidiary) to another entity, or YourMembership (or a division or subsidiary) is acquired by or merged with another entity, you agree that YourMembership may provide to such entity customer information that is related to that part of our business that was sold to or merged with the other entity without obtaining your further consent.

**Withdrawal of privacy consent**  
If the collection of your personal data was based on your consent, you have the right to revoke that consent at any time. Be aware that by revoking consent, you may lose access to services you previously opted to use.

You may request to review, correct, delete, or otherwise modify any of the personal information that you have previously provided to us. If you are a direct client of YourMembership, you can do so at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number provided in the section entitled “How to Contact Us”.  
We may need to verify your identity to respond to your request. Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be addressed within a reasonable timeframe and in accordance with applicable data protection laws. If we can’t give you access, we will tell you why in writing and how you can make a complaint about our decision. If you are an “end-user”, in other words, a customer of one of our clients, please contact that organization directly to modify any of your personal information.

### Further Details on Changes to the Privacy Policy

The data YourMembership collects and uses is governed by this Privacy Policy as amended from time to time, not by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of data collection. This includes data collected from YourMembership Websites, affiliates with links to this Privacy Policy, and services provided by or enabled via these sites. YourMembership may change the Privacy Policy at our sole discretion and will provide notice of changes in the Privacy Policy and on the privacy policy page of our Websites. If, as the result of such changes, you want to alter the ways in which we are allowed to use your personal information, you can do so by following the procedure described in the section entitled “Privacy Rights”.

Please regularly review our Privacy Policy. If you have objections to the Privacy Policy, you should immediately discontinue use of the Websites and the Services enabled by the Websites. This Privacy Policy does not govern privacy practices associated with offline activities, websites other than the Websites, or any products or services not available or enabled via the Websites.

You will be deemed to have been made aware of, and will be subject to, the changes to the Privacy Policy after such notice has been posted with the following exception: if at the time you provide personal information to YourMembership you limit how such information will be used to communicate with you, either by YourMembership or by third parties, YourMembership will not change your preference in this regard without your express consent.

### How to Contact Us

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles and applicable data protection laws, YourMembership commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. YourMembership takes its users’ privacy concerns seriously and is committed to resolving privacy complaints.

If you believe that YourMembership has not complied with this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information, or you have questions about privacy related issues or the handling of your personal information, or you are an EU individual with an inquiry or complaint regarding our Privacy Shield policy, or you wish to raise any other complaint in respect of privacy, you should first contact us at YourMembership by emailing us at [privacy.yourmembership@communitybrands.com](mailto:privacy.yourmembership@communitybrands.com) or by writing to the YourMembership Privacy Office at the following address: YourMembership

Attn: YourMembership Privacy Office  
9620 Executive Center Dr. N #200  
St. Petersburg, FL 33702  
USA

In your correspondence, please describe in as much detail as possible the ways in which you believe that the Privacy Policy or Privacy Shield Framework has not been complied with or the nature of your other complaint or inquiry. We will investigate your complaint promptly.

YourMembership has committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if it is not satisfactorily addressed by YourMembership, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/for more information and to file a complaint. Should you not receive a satisfactory resolution, you may also contact your local data protection authority, the Federal Trade Commission, or the US Department of Commerce. Finally, if your complaint remains unresolved, you have the right to invoke binding arbitration by the Privacy Shield Panel upon written notice to YourMembership at [privacy.yourmembership@communitybrands.com](mailto:privacy.yourmembership@communitybrands.com).

For EEA residents, you can find the contact details for your local data protection authority here <https://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>

For Australian residents, your local data protection authority is the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

For Australian residents, if you do not receive acknowledgement of your complaint within thirty days as outlined in this “How to Contact Us” section above, or if you are dissatisfied with the response from YourMembership, please contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner using the contact details below.

Phone: 1300 363 992  
Email: [enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au)  
Online: [www.oaic.gov.au/privacy](https://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy)

Please note that YourMembership is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of non- YourMembership websites to which this Website or any other YourMembership website may link. Also, YourMembership is not responsible for the privacy practices of its customers or users  
of its customer websites. You should review the additional privacy policy of the customer website before using the website.

Effective: June 25, 2019
